SCOTT VOGEL

(510) 847-4683 | scottokinawa@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/scott-vogel-a7a02464/

Github: https://github.com/scottokinawa

Raised in Japan by a Chilean mom, an American/Mexican dad, and while attending an American school, I am no stranger to translating. I utilize my experience in translating to help explain complex problems and solutions for all to understand.

SKILLS

Python, Machine Learning, SQL, Web-Scraping, Tableau, Excel and Microsoft Access, Japanese (Fluent-Verbal) and Spanish (Conversational)

EXPERIENCE

Data Science Immersive Student | Washington D.C.

September 2017 – December 2017

General Assembly

- Learned applicable Data Science skills in an intensive 65hr/week program.
- Wrote a Convolutional Neural Network algorithm to differentiate human faces.
- Created a functional pipeline on how to increase user interaction for a D.C. analytics company.
- Web scraped Reddit to analyze user posts and forecast what features would increase popularity.
- Acquired, cleaned and analyzed large datasets using python packages such as Pandas and Scikit-Learn.

Associate Consultant | San Francisco, California

June 2016 – September 2017

Triage Consulting Group

- Researched around 40K row datasets to collect over 200K worth of underpayments every month.
- Created and worked on dashboards for internal teams.
- Utilized Excel, SQL and Microsoft Access to identify complex risk areas earning returns of 5K-400K.
- Created macro SQL queries to streamline data processes to cut 30 minutes off everyday tasks.
- Prepared 2-3 monthly financial reports to forecast progress and project profitability for management.

Consulting Internship | Reston, Virginia

May – August 2015

Maximus

- Spearheaded the Global Mobility Program, which consisted of managing 8 expatriates.
- Identified and evaluated global mobility providers to minimize vendor costs.
- Analyzed expatriate expense documentation to identify potential project savings of 600K.
- Collaborated with global mobility vendors to manage the expatriate projects.

Berkeley Cooperative House Manager | UC Berkeley

January 2014 – September 2016

Berkeley Student Cooperative

- Financed and regulated a 40K budget of a 56-person household.
- Fostered a better relationship with corporate, and served as their point person.
- Implemented new house policies that increased safer space, compared to previous semesters.

EDUCATION

General Assembly, Washington D.C

Data Science Immersive Program

University of California, Berkeley

B.S. Environmental Economics and Policy

Graduated: Dec 2017

Graduated: May 2016